<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE I2CEConfiguration PUBLIC "SYSTEM"
"I2CE_Configuration.dtd">
<I2CEConfiguration name="isco-88-major-07">
  <metadata>
    <displayName>ISCO 88 Job Codes</displayName>
    <description>The ISCO 88 Job Codes</description>
    <version>4.3.0</version>
    <requirement name="isco-88">
      <atLeast version="4.3" />
      <lessThan version="4.4" />
    </requirement>
  </metadata>
  <configurationGroup name="formsData" path="/I2CE/formsData/forms">
    <displayName>Forms Data</displayName>
    <description>Form data saved in magic data</description>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_major">
      <configurationGroup name="7">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>CRAFT AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Miners, shotfirers, stone cutters and carvers extract solid minerals from underground or surface mines or quarries, charge and detonate explosives, or cut and shape stone for building and other purposes. Tasks performed usually include: extracting solid minerals from underground or surface mines or quarries; charging and detonating explosives in mines, quarries, building sites and other places; cutting and shaping stone for building and other purposes. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_sub_major">
      <configurationGroup name="71">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>EXTRACTION AND BUILDING TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Miners and quarry workers extract solid minerals from underground or surface mines or quarries. Tasks include - (a) extracting coal, ores and other solid minerals from underground or surface mines; (b) extracting granite, limestone, slate, flint or other kinds of rocks from quarries; (c) setting and operating machines which cut channels or drill blasting holes into the open face of mines or quarries; (d) cutting, fitting and installing wood or steel props, pillars and arches to support walls and roof of underground workings; (e) collecting samples of coal or ore for laboratory analysis; (f) extracting chalk, clay, gravel or sand from open pits; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|7</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="72">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>METAL, MACHINERY AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal moulders,welders, sheet-metalworkers, structural-metal preparers and related trades workers make moulds and cores for casting metal, weld and cut metal parts, make and repair articles of sheet metal, install, erect, maintain and repair heavy metal structures, tackle, cable-cars and related equipment, or carry out similar work under water. Tasks performed usually include: making moulds and cores for casting metal; casting, welding and shaping metal parts; making and repairing articles of sheet metal such as sheet steel, copper, tin or brass; installing, erecting, maintaining and repairing heavy metal structures, as well as tackle, cable cars and related equipment; carrying out similar work under water. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|7</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="73">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PRECISION, HANDICRAFT, PRINTING AND RELATED TRADES</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Precision, handicraft, printing and related trades workers make and repair precision instruments, musical instruments, various articles such as jewellery, precious metalware, ceramics, porcelain ware and glassware, as well as handicrafts made of wood or textile, leather or related materials, or they perform printing or book-binding tasks. The work is carried out by hand and by hand-powered and other tools which are used to reduce the amount of physical effort and time required for specific tasks, as well as to improve the quality of the products. The tasks call for an understanding of the work organisation, the materials and tools used, and the nature and purpose of the final product. Tasks performed by workers in this sub-major group usually include: making and repairing nautical, meteorological, optical and other precision instruments and equipment; making and repairing musical instruments; making jewellery and precious metalware; making pottery, porcelain ware, ceramics and glassware; painting and decorating various articles; producing handicraft articles in wood or textile, leather and related materials; performing printing or book-binding tasks. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|7</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="74">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>OTHER CRAFT AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Other craft and related trades workers treat and process agricultural and fisheries raw materials into food and other products, and produce and repair goods made of wood, textiles, fur, leather, or other materials. The work is carried out by hand and by hand-powered and other tools which are used to reduce the amount of physical effort and time required for specific tasks, as well as to improve the quality of the products. The tasks call for an understanding of the work organisation, the materials and tools used, and the nature and purpose of the final product. Tasks performed by this sub-major group usually include: treating and processing meat, fish, grain, fruit, vegetables and related materials into food stuffs, and tobacco into tobacco products; tasting and grading food products and beverages; treating and processing natural fibres, skins and hides; making and repairing furniture and other goods made of wood; preparing hides, skins and pelts for further use; making and repairing textiles, garments, hats, shoes and related products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|7</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_minor">
      <configurationGroup name="711">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>MINERS, SHOTFIRERS, STONE CUTTERS AND CARVERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Shotfirers and blasters determine location and force of explosions required, charge and detonate explosives to fragment or dislodge coal, ores, rock or other solid minerals in mines or quarries, or to clear building sites and similar places. Tasks include - (a) ensuring observance of workplace safety procedures and regulations; (b) determining location of explosions required and giving instructions on holes to be drilled; (c) deciding on force required and placing correct quantity of explosives, and preparing blasting site; (d) firing blasting-charge in mines or quarries; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|71</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="712">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>BUILDING FRAME AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bricklayers and stonemasons erect and repair foundations, walls and structures of brick, stone and similar materials. Tasks include - (a) laying stone, brick, hollow tile and similar building blocks to construct or repair walls, partitions, fireplaces and other structures such as smokestacks, furnaces, converters, kilns and ovens, piers and abutments; (b) laying walks, curbs and pavements of stone; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|71</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="713">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>BUILDING FINISHERS AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Roofers cover, maintain and repair roof frameworks with one or more kinds of material. Tasks include - (a) covering roof frameworks with slates and tiles, synthetic materials, asphalt, metal sheets, or thatching materials; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|71</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="714">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PAINTERS, BUILDING STRUCTURE CLEANERS AND RELATED WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Painters and related workers prepare surfaces of buildings and other structures for painting, apply protective and decorative coats of paint or similar materials or cover interior walls and ceilings of buildings with wallpaper, silk or other fabrics. Tasks include - (a) cleaning and preparing walls and other surfaces of buildings for painting or wallpapering; (b) applying or spraying paint, varnish, shellac and similar materials to surfaces, fixtures and fittings of buildings; (c) measuring and mounting wallpaper, silk or other fabrics on interior walls and ceilings of buildings and ships; (d) applying or spraying paint, red lead, bituminous emulsion and similar materials to ships\' hulls and metal structures, steel frameworks of buildings, bridges and metal constructions; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers in this group.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|71</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="721">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>METAL MOULDERS, WELDERS, SHEET-METAL WORKERS, STRUCTURAL- PREPARERS, AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal moulders and coremakers make moulds and cores for casting metal. Tasks include - (a) making moulds by hand or by using auxiliary machines on a bench for small metal castings, or on the foundry floor or in a pit for large castings; (b) making cores for use in metal moulds; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|72</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="722">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>BLACKSMITHS, TOOL-MAKERS AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Blacksmiths, hammer-smiths and forging-press workers draw wire, hammer and forge bars, rods, ingots and plates of iron, steel or other metals to make and repair various kinds of tools, metal articles, pieces of equipment, agricultural and related implements. Tasks include - (a) heating metal in forge furnace and manufacturing and repairing articles by drawing, bending, cutting, hammering metal on an anvil, punching, shearing, joining and hardening or tempering; (b) shaping heated metal into forgings on power hammer equipped with open dies; (c) operating closed-die drop hammer to forge metal articles; (d) operating a power-press machine equipped with closed dies to forge metal articles; (e) drawing wire; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|72</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="723">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>MACHINERY MECHANICS AND FITTERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Motor vehicle mechanics and fitters fit, install, maintain, service and repair engines and the mechanical and related equipment of motor cycles, passenger cars and delivery trucks and other motor vehicles. Tasks include - (a) fitting, examining, testing and servicing motor vehicle engines; (b) replacing engine components or complete engines; (c) fitting, examining, adjusting, dismantling, rebuilding and replacing defective parts of motor vehicles; (d) installing or adjusting motors and brakes, and adjusting steering or other parts of motor vehicles; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|72</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="724">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC EQUIPMENT MECHANICS AND</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electrical and electronic equipment mechanics and fitters adjust, install and repair electrical and electronic equipment such as computer hardware, sound and image recording and telecommunications systems, and construct, install and repair electrical lines and joint cables. Tasks performed usually include: fitting, adjusting and repairing electrical machinery and equipment; fitting, adjusting, servicing and repairing computer hardware and other electronic products; servicing and repairing radio, television and hi-fi sound equipment; installing, servicing and repairing telegraph and telephone equipment; installing and repairing electrical lines and jointing cables. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|72</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="731">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PRECISION WORKERS IN METAL AND RELATED</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Precision workers in metal and related materials make and repair precision instruments, musical instruments, jewellery and other articles of precious metals. Tasks performed usually include: making and repairing watches, clocks, nautical, meteorological, optical, surgical, dental, orthopaedic and other precision instruments and equipment; making and repairing musical instruments; cutting or setting gems, and making and repairing jewellery and precious metalware. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|73</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="732">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>POTTERS, GLASS-MAKERS AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Potters, glass-makers and related trades workers make bricks, tiles, pottery, porcelain ware and glassware, engrave and etch designs on glass articles, and paint or decorate glass, ceramics and related articles and signs. Tasks performed usually include: making abrasive wheels, pottery, porcelain ware, bricks and tiles; making glassware; engraving and etching designs on glass articles; decorating glass and ceramic articles; applying decorative coatings of paint and similar materials to various articles, or applying letters and designs to signs. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|73</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="733">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>HANDICRAFT WORKERS IN WOOD,TEXTILE, LEATHER AND MATERIALS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Handicraft workers in wood, textile, leather and related materials apply traditional techniques to produce various articles for personal or household use, as well as for decorative purposes. Tasks performed usually include: preparing wood, straw, rattan, reeds, bone, stone, shells and other materials; carving, moulding, assembling, painting and decorating various articles; weaving, knitting, embroidering, lace-making; producing traditional footwear; producing handbags, belts and other accessories. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|73</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="734">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PRINTING AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Printing and related trades workers set and arrange printing type or copy by hand or by electronic key-boarding or other machines, make printing plates from typographically or electronically set-up type or copy, engrave lithographic stones, printing plates and rollers, make and print with silk-screens, print on paper and other materials, or bind and finish books. Tasks performed usually include: setting and arranging printing type or copy by hand or by electronic key-boarding or other machines: making printing plates from typographically or electronically set-up type or copy; engraving lithographic stones, printing plates, rollers, dies and blocks; making and printing with silk-screens; printing on paper and other materials; binding covers to books and performing book-finishing operations. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|73</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="741">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>FOOD PROCESSING AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Food processing and related trades workers slaughter animals, kill fish, treat and prepare them and related food items for human and animal consumption, make various kinds of bread, cakes and other flour products, process and preserve fruit, vegetables and related foods, taste and grade various food products and beverages, or prepare tobacco and make tobacco products. Tasks performed usually include: slaughtering animals; killing fish; treating meat and fish and preparing them and related food items; making various kinds of bread, cakes and other flour products; processing and preserving fruit, vegetables and related foods; tasting and grading various food products and beverages; preparing tobacco and making tobacco products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|74</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="742">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>WOOD TREATERS, CABINET-MAKERS AND RELATED TRADES</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood treaters, cabinet-makers, and related trades workers season and carve wood and wooden items, make and repair wooden furniture, wooden fittings, patterns and models, by using tools and woodworking machines; set or set and operate woodworking machines, make wicker furniture and related articles, and decorate and repair wooden articles and wooden parts of goods. Tasks performed usually include: seasoning and preserving wood; making, decorating and repairing wooden furniture; making, decorating and repairing parts of or entire wooden vehicles, wooden models, patterns, and various articles such as pipes, wooden skis, shoes, or sports goods; setting or setting and operating woodworking machines such as those for precision sawing, shaping or carving; making wicker furniture, baskets and similar items, or brooms and brushes. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|74</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="743">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>TEXTILE, GARMENT AND RELATED TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Textile, garment and related trades workers prepare natural textile fibres, threads and yarns, and make fabrics by weaving, knitting and other means, make and repair garments and other textile and fur articles, or they upholster furniture. Tasks performed usually include: preparing natural textile fibres, spinning, doubling, twisting and winding threads and yarns; making fabrics by weaving, knitting and other techniques; making tailored garments; participating in the manufacture of ready-to-wear garments; making, altering and repairing articles made of fur; making patterns and marking and cutting textiles and similar materials; sewing textiles and similar materials by hand or hand-operated machines; upholstering furniture and making mattresses. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|74</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="744">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PELT, LEATHER AND SHOEMAKING TRADES WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Pelt, leather and shoemaking trades workers prepare fur- and wool-bean pelts for further use, make leather from hides and skins, make and repair footwear and other articles made of natural or synthetic leather with the exception of garments, hats and gloves, or make various other articles from leather and similar materials. Tasks performed usually include: preparing fur- and wool- bearing pelts for making garments and other products by hand or by using simple tools; making leather from hides and skins; making and repairing footwear and other articles made from leather and similar materials, with the exception of garments, hats and gloves. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|74</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_unit">
      <configurationGroup name="7111">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Miners and quarry workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Stone splitters, cutters and carvers break quarried stone slabs or blocks, or by using hand or hand-powered tools cut, shape and finish stone for building, ornamental, monumental and other purposes. Tasks include - (a) driving wedges into quarried stone to break it into slabs or blocks; (b) selecting and grading slabs and blocks of granite, marble, and other stone; (c) cutting, shaping and finishing building and monumental stone such as granite or marble by using hand or hand-powered tools; (d) making patterns and marking shapes on stone for subsequent sawing, planing, drilling and other dressing and cutting operations; (e) cutting and carving characters, figures or designs on stone blocks used for monuments or memorials; (f) setting stone in the erection of monuments and memorials; (g) cutting and carving characters, figures or designs on stone used for decorative facings on buildings- (h) performing related tasks; (i) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|711</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7112">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Shotfirers and blasters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Building frame and related trades workers construct, maintain and repair foundations, walls and other main parts of buildings and other constructions, both internally and externally. Tasks performed usually include: erecting and repairing small and large buildings and other structures by using traditional building techniques and materials such as bamboo, hay, straw or mud; erecting and repairing foundations, walls and structures of brick, stone and similar materials; erecting reinforced concrete frameworks and structures and finishing cement surfaces; erecting and repairing various types of wooden structures and fittings; performing miscellaneous construction and building maintenance tasks. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|711</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7113">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Stone splitters, cutters and carvers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Builders, traditional materials erect, maintain and repair small and large buildings and other structures by using traditional building techniques and materials such as bamboo, hay, straw, reeds, mud, planks, poles or leaves. Tasks include - (a) preparing ground for erecting building or other structures; (b) collecting necessary materials; (c) erecting structures to support roof, and building and covering walls with mud, straw or other materials; (d) fixing rafters to roof and covering with roofing material; (e) levelling floor to make it smooth and serviceable; (f) maintaining and repairing existing structures; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|711</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7121">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Builders, traditional materials</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bricklayers and stonemasons erect and repair foundations, walls and structures of brick, stone and similar materials. Tasks include - (a) laying stone, brick, hollow tile and similar building blocks to construct or repair walls, partitions, fireplaces and other structures such as smokestacks, furnaces, converters, kilns and ovens, piers and abutments; (b) laying walks, curbs and pavements of stone; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|712</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7122">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bricklayers and stonemasons</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Concrete placers, concrete finishers and related workers erect reinforced concrete frameworks and structures, make forms for moulding concrete, reinforce concrete surfaces, cement openings in walls or casings for wells, finish and repair cement surfaces and carry out terrazzo work. Tasks include - (a) constructing and repairing reinforced concrete floors, walls, tanks, silos and other concrete structures; (b) making shuttering or assembling prefabricated forms for moulding concrete; (c) cementing openings in walls or casings for wells; (d) finishing and smoothing surfaces of concrete structures; (e) applying a durable, smooth surfacing composed of cement, sand pigment and marble particles to floors, known as a terrazzo finish; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|712</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7123">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Concrete placers, concrete finishers and related</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Carpenters and joiners cut, shape, assemble, erect, maintain and repair various types of wooden structures and fittings. Tasks include - (a) making, altering and repairing structural and other woodwork at a work-bench and on a construction site; (b) constructing, erecting and installing heavy-framed wooden structures on building sites; (c) fitting, assembling and altering internal and external fixtures of buildings, such as walls, doors, door and window frames, facings and panelling; (d) making, repairing and fitting scenic equipment for theatrical performances, motion picture or television productions; (e) constructing, assembling, altering and repairing wooden fixtures and fittings in train coaches, aircraft, ships, boats, floats, pontoons and other vehicles; (f) cutting, shaping, fitting and assembling wooden parts, mainly at a work-bench; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|712</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7124">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Carpenters and joiners</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>This unit group covers building frame and related trades workers not classified elsewhere in Minor group 712, Building frame and related trades workers. For instance, here should be classified those who perform miscellaneous construction and building maintenance tasks. In such cases tasks would include - (a) performing miscellaneous construction and building maintenance work on structures such as office buildings, apartment houses, factories and similar establishments in good repair; (b) performing construction, maintenance or repair work at unusual heights; (c) erecting temporary metal or wooden scaffolding on building sites; (d) demolishing buildings and other structures; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|712</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7129">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Building frame and related trades workers elsewhere classified</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Building finishers and related trades workers cover, apply or install, maintain and repair roofs, floors, walls, insulation systems, glass in windows or other frames, as well as plumbing, piping and electrical systems in buildings and other constructions. Tasks performed usually include: covering roof frameworks with one or more kinds of material; installing parquet and other kinds of flooring or covering floors and walls with tiles or mosaic panels; applying plaster to walls and ceilings; applying insulating material to walls, floors and ceilings; cutting, fitting and setting glass in windows and similar openings; installing plumbing and pipeline systems; installing electrical wiring and related equipment. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|712</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7131">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Roofers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Floor layers and tile setters install, maintain and repair parquet and other kinds of flooring, or they cover floors, walls and other surfaces with tiles or mosaic panels for decorative or other purposes. Tasks include - (a) preparing floor areas for covering with parquet, tiles or other materials; (b) assembling parquetry pieces or other materials and laying them on floors according to design and other specifications; (c) preparing wall areas for covering with tiles or other materials for decorative or other purposes such as acoustical insulation; (d) setting tiles and constructing and laying mosaic panels to walls, floors and other surfaces; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7132">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Floor layers and tile setters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Plasterers install and repair laths and apply plaster to walls and ceilings of buildings. Tasks include - (a) installing and repairing laths and applying one or more coats of plaster to interior walls and ceilings of buildings to produce finished surface; (b) moulding and installing ornamental plaster panels and casting and trimming ornamental plaster cornices; (c) applying protective and decorative covering of cement, plaster and similar materials to exterior building surfaces; (d) making and installing decorative plaster fixtures of fibrous plaster; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7133">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Plasterers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Insulation workers apply and repair insulating materials to buildings, boilers, pipes or refrigeration and air-conditioning equipment. Tasks include - (a) applying slabs and sheets of insulating or sound-absorbing materials to walls, floors and ceilings of buildings; (b) blowing and packing insulating or sound-absorbing materials into cavities between walls, floors and ceilings of buildings with power-driven machines (c) applying insulating materials to exposed surfaces of equipment such as boilers, pipes and tanks; (d) insulating refrigeration and air-conditioning equipment; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7134">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Insulation workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glaziers cut, fit and set glass in windows, doors, shop fronts and other frames. Tasks include - (a) selecting glass panes, cutting them to measure and fixing them in windows, doors and partitions of buildings; (b) fastening glass panes in skylights; (c) installing flat or curved glass in shop fronts, swing-doors, show-cases, portholes or other openings; (d) cutting, assembling and installing pieces of glass in lead or copper framework to form decorative windows and panels; (e) installing ordinary or shatter-proof glass panels in windows, doors and windscreens of vehicles; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7135">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glaziers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Plumbers and pipe fitters assemble, fit, install and repair plumbing fixtures, or pipes and pipeline systems. Tasks include - (a) cutting, threading, bending, jointing, assembling, installing, maintaining and repairing pipes, fittings and fixtures of drainage, heating, water supply and sewerage systems; (b) assembling, installing, maintaining and repairing pipeline systems in ships, aircraft, buildings, industrial plant, etc.; (c) laying clay, concrete or cast-iron pipes in ditches to form sewers, drains or water mains, or for other purposes; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers. Examples of the occupations classified here:</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7136">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Plumbers and pipe fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Building and related electricians install, maintain and repair electrical wiring systems and related equipment. Tasks include - (a) installing, maintaining and repairing electrical wiring systems and related equipment in various buildings such as schools, hospitals, commercial establishments, residential buildings and other structures; (b) installing, maintaining and repairing electrical equipment in theatres and radio or television studios; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7137">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Building and related electricians</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Painters, building structure cleaners and related trades workers prepare surfaces, apply paint and similar materials to buildings and other structures, vehicles, or various manufactured articles, cover interior walls and ceilings with wallpaper, clean chimneys and exterior surfaces of buildings and other structures. Tasks performed usually include: preparing surfaces and applying paint and similar materials to buildings and other structures; applying paint or varnish to vehicles or various manufactured articles, usually with a hand-spraying device; covering interior walls and ceilings with wallpaper, silk or other fabrics; cleaning chimneys; cleaning exterior surfaces of buildings and other structures. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|713</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7141">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Painters and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Varnishers and related painters paint vehicles such as cars, buses or trucks, or apply protective coats of enamel or varnish on metal, wooden and other manufactured articles, usually with a hand-spraying device. Tasks include - (a) painting cars, buses, trucks and other vehicles, and applying varnish and other protective coatings; (b) applying paint as well as protective coatings of enamel or varnish on metal, wooden and other manufactured products, usually with a hand-spraying device; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|714</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7142">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Varnishers and related painters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Building structure cleaners remove soot from chimneys, or clean exterior surfaces of buildings and other structures. Tasks include - (a) removing soot from flues, chimneys and connecting pipes; (b) cleaning exterior surfaces of stone, brick, metal or similar materials by means of chemicals, of a jet of steam or sand applied under great pressure; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|714</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7143">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Building structure cleaners</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal, machinery and related trades workers cast, weld, forge and, by other methods, form metal, erect, maintain and repair heavy metal structures, engage in machine-tool setting as well as in fitting, maintaining and repairing machinery, including engines, vehicles, electrical and electronic equipment, or they produce tools and various non-precious-metal articles. The work is carried out by hand and by hand-powered and other tools which are used to reduce the amount of physical effort and time required for specific tasks, as well as to improve the quality of the products. The tasks call for an understanding of the work organisation, the materials and tools used, and the nature and purpose of the final product. Tasks performed by workers in this sub-major group usually include: making moulds and cores for casting metal; casting, welding and shaping metal; installing, erecting, maintaining and repairing heavy metal structures, tackle and related equipment; forging and forming steel and other non-precious metals to make and repair machinery, tools, equipment and other articles; setting for operators or setting and operating various machine tools; fitting, maintaining and repairing industrial machinery, including engines and vehicles, as well as electrical and electronic instruments and other equipment. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|714</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7211">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal moulders and coremakers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Welders and flame cutters weld and cut metal parts using gas flame, or an electric arc and other sources of heat to melt and cut, or to melt and fuse metal. Tasks include - (a) welding metal parts using gas flame, or an electric arc, thermite compound or other methods; (b) operating resistance-welding machines; (c) using blowtorch to make and repair lead linings, pipes, floors and other lead fixtures; (d) brazing metal parts together; (e) cutting metal pieces using gas flame or an electric arc; (f) joining metal parts by hand soldering; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7212">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Welders and flamecutters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Sheet-metal workers make, install and repair articles and parts of articles of sheet metal such as sheet steel, copper, tin, brass, aluminium, zinc or galvanised iron. Tasks include - (a) marking sheet metal for cutting and shaping; (b) making and repairing household utensils and other articles in tin, copper and light alloys, or ornamental articles and fittings; (c) making and repairing boilers, tanks, vats and similar containers; (d) installing and repairing sheet-metal parts of vehicles and aircraft; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7213">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Sheet metal workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Structural-metal preparers and erectors shape, assemble and erect heavy metal girders and plates to form structures and frameworks. Tasks include - (a) marking metal members as a guide when drilling, cutting, and shaping them for use in buildings, ships and other structures; (b) drilling, cutting and shaping structural steel in a workshop; (c) erecting steel members for buildings, bridges and other constructions; (d) assembling and erecting the framework and other metal parts of ships\' structures; (e) shaping and fitting structural-steel plates of ships under construction or repair; (f) riveting structural-metal members by hand, machine or pneumatic riveter; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7214">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Structural-metal preparers and erectors</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Riggers and cable splicers erect tackle for lifting and hauling,\' or install and maintain cables, ropes and wires on construction sites, oil- and gas-well drilling sites, or in ships, aircraft, and other places. Tasks include - (a) setting up various types of cages, funicular railways, aerial cableways, moving platforms, lifting tackle and other hoisting equipment for moving passengers, workers, materials, machinery and other heavy objects in mountainous areas, across deep gorges or fjords, about workshops, shipyards, or other locations; (b) joining, repairing and fitting attachments to wires, hemp ropes and cables; (c) installing and repairing ropes, wires and cables on ships and aircraft; (d) working as member of crew erecting and repairing derricks for drilling water, gas- and oil-wells and installing cables, hoisting and drilling equipment; (e) working as member of cable crew fitting and installing wire cables in the construction of suspension bridges, (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7215">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Riggers and cable splicers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Underwater workers work under water, dressed in scuba gear or diving suit, to inspect, install, repair, and remove equipment and structures. Tasks include - (a) working under water to lay and repair bridges, piers and harbour-wall foundations; (b) inspecting for suspected damage and making minor repairs to ships\' hulls and underwater installations; (c) reporting on condition of wrecked ships; (d) removing underwater obstructions; (e) drilling holes for underwater blasting; (f) performing various underwater tasks connected with salvage work or recovering dead bodies; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7216">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Underwater workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Blacksmiths, tool-makers and related trades workers hammer and forge bars, rods or ingots of iron, steel and other metals to make and repair various kinds of tools, equipment and other articles, set for operators or set and operate various machine tools, and polish and sharpen metal surfaces. Tasks performed usually include: hammering and forging iron, steel and other metals to make and repair various kinds of tools, equipment and other articles; setting for operators or setting and operating various machine tools working to fine tolerances; polishing and sharpening metal surfaces and tools. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|721</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7221">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Blacksmiths, hammer-smiths and forging-press workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Tool-makers and related workers make and repair tools, sports guns, locks, dies, patterns and other metal articles, as well as make engines or machinery components, and parts thereof, using hand and machine tools to work metal to fine tolerances. Tasks include - (a) making, maintaining and repairing dies, jigs, gauges and fixtures, using hand tools and various kinds of machine tools; (b) making engines or machinery components, and parts thereof; (c) fitting and assembling parts to make and repair jigs, fixtures and gauges; (d) repairing and modifying sports guns and other small arms; (e) making, fitting, assembling, repairing and installing lock parts and locks; (f) making and repairing metal patterns for preparation of foundry moulds; (g) laying out lines and reference points on metal stock to guide other workers who cut, turn, mill, grind or otherwise shape metal; (h) performing related tasks; (i) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|722</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7222">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Tool-makers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Machine-tool setters and setter-operators set for operators, or set and operate, various machine tools working to fine tolerances. Tasks include - (a) setting one or more types of machine tools for operators to produce metal articles in standardised series; (b) setting and operating a variety of machine tools; (c) setting and operating particular types of metalworking machines, such as lathe, milling, planing, boring, drilling, grinding or honing machines, including multipurpose numerically controlled metalworking machines; (d) performing similar tasks when machining plastics and other metal substitutes; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|722</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7223">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Machine-tool setters and setter-operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal wheel-grinders, polishers and tool sharpeners grind and polish metal surfaces and sharpen tools. Tasks include - (a) operating fixed or portable buffing and polishing machines; (b) sharpening cutting tools and instruments using grinding wheel or mechanically operated grinding machines; (c) repairing, adjusting and sharpening saw blades and metal teeth of cylinders in textile carding machines; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|722</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7224">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal wheel-grinders, polishers and tool sharpeners</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Machinery mechanics and fitters fit, install, maintain and repair engines, vehicles, agricultural or industrial machinery, and mechanical equipment. Tasks performed usually include: fitting, installing, maintaining and repairing engines, vehicles, agricultural or industrial machinery, and mechanical equipment. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|722</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7231">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Motor vehicle mechanics and fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Aircraft engine mechanics and fitters fit, service, repair and overhaul aircraft engines. Tasks include - (a) fitting, examining, testing and servicing aircraft engines; (b) replacing engine components or complete engines; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|723</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7232">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Aircraft engine mechanics and fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Agricultural- or industrial-machinery mechanics and fitters fit, install, examine, service and repair engines (except motor vehicle and aircraft engines), agricultural or industrial machinery and mechanical equipment. Tasks include - (a) fitting, installing, examining, servicing and repairing engines (except motor vehicle and aircraft engines), agricultural or industrial machinery and mechanical equipment; (b) oiling and greasing stationary engines, machinery and vehicles; (c) inspecting and testing new machinery and mechanical equipment for conformity with standards and specifications; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|723</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7233">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Agricultural- or industrial-machinery mechanics and fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electrical and electronic equipment mechanics and fitters adjust, install and repair electrical and electronic equipment such as computer hardware, sound and image recording and telecommunications systems, and construct, install and repair electrical lines and joint cables. Tasks performed usually include: fitting, adjusting and repairing electrical machinery and equipment; fitting, adjusting, servicing and repairing computer hardware and other electronic products; servicing and repairing radio, television and hi-fi sound equipment; installing, servicing and repairing telegraph and telephone equipment; installing and repairing electrical lines and jointing cables. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|723</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7241">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electrical mechanics and fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electrical mechanics and fitters fit, adjust, install and repair electrical machinery and other electrical apparatus and equipment in buildings, factories, workshops, or other places. Tasks include - (a) fitting, adjusting and repairing various kinds of electrical machinery and motors, generators, switchgear and control apparatus, instruments, or electrical parts of elevators and related equipment; (b) fitting, adjusting and repairing electrical parts in domestic appliances, industrial machines and other appliances, or electrical apparatus in aircraft, ships and vehicles; (c) inspecting and testing manufactured electrical products; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|724</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7242">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electronics fitters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electronics fitters fit and adjust computer hardware, as well as sound and image recording and transmitting telecommunications and other electronic equipment. Tasks include - (a) fitting and adjusting computer hardware, sound and image recorders and transmitters, radar equipment, electronic components of musical instruments, medical or industrial equipment and signalling systems; (b) inspecting and testing manufactured electronic products; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|724</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7243">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electronics mechanics and servicers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electronics mechanics and servicers service and repair radio and television equipment, tape recorders, video cassette recorders, and other audio-visual equipment. Tasks include - (a) examining radio or television equipment, tape recorders, video cassette recorders, and other audio-visual equipment, replacing defective parts and making adjustments and repairs; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|724</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7244">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Telegraph and telephone installers and servicers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Telegraph and telephone installers and servicers install, service and repair telephone and telegraph equipment in central sites or individual locations. Tasks include - (a) installing, servicing and repairing telephone and telegraph equipment in central sites or individual locations; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|724</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7245">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electrical line installers, repairers and cable</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electrical line installers, repairers and cable jointers install and repair electrical lines and joint cables. Tasks include - (a) installing and repairing overhead and underground electrical power and electrical traction lines; (b) installing and repairing overhead and underground telephone and telegraph lines; (c) making joints in overhead and underground cables; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|724</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7311">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Precision-instrument makers and repairers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Precision-instrument makers and repairers make and repair mechanical watches, clocks, nautical, meteorological, optical, surgical, dental, orthopaedic and other precision instruments and equipment. Tasks include - (a) making, adjusting and repairing mechanical watches and clocks; (b) making, adjusting and repairing nautical and meteorological instruments and equipment; (c) making, adjusting and repairing optical instruments; (d) making, adjusting and repairing surgical instruments and other medical equipment; (e) making and repairing medical, orthopaedic and dental appliances and prostheses; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|731</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7312">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Musical instrument makers and tuners</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Musical-instrument makers and tuners make, repair and tune stringed, wind or percussion instruments with hand or power tools. Tasks include (a) making and repairing accordions, stringed and wind instruments; (b) building and repairing organs and making parts for such organs; (c) making instrumental parts of pianos and assembling and repairing such pianos; (d) tuning organs, pianos and other instruments; (e) making and repairing other musical instruments; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|731</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7313">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Jewelery and precious-metal workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Jewellery and precious-metal workers make and repair jewellery and precious metalware, cut and set gems and engrave designs on jewellery and precious metal articles. Tasks include - (a) casting jewellery and other non-ferrous metal articles by hand; (b) making complete jewellery articles such as rings, brooches and bracelets; (c) cutting and polishing gems and setting them in jewellery articles; (d) making and repairing precious metalware; (e) rolling and beating precious metals; engraving letters and designs on jewellery and precious metalware; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|731</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7321">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Abrasive wheel formers, potters and related</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Jewellery and precious-metal workers make and repair jewellery and precious metalware, cut and set gems and engrave designs on jewellery and precious metal articles. Tasks include - (a) casting jewellery and other non-ferrous metal articles by hand; (b) making complete jewellery articles such as rings, brooches and bracelets; (c) cutting and polishing gems and setting them in jewellery articles; (d) making and repairing precious metalware; (e) rolling and beating precious metals; engraving letters and designs on jewellery and precious metalware; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|732</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7322">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glass makers, cutters, grinders and finishers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glass-makers, cutters, grinders and finishers blow, mould, press and roll shapes from molten glass and cut, grind and polish glass. Tasks include - (a) shaping molten glass by means of blowpipe, hand moulding, heating and bending; (b) heating, moulding and pressing optical glass to make lens blanks; (c) grinding and polishing lens blanks; (d) grinding and bevelling edges of glass; (e) cutting sheet glass with hand tools and sawing prisms and other shapes from optical glass blocks; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|732</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7323">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glass engravers and etchers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glass engravers and etchers engrave and etch designs on glass articles. Tasks include - (a) engraving monograms and ornamental designs on glassware; (b) etching decorative designs, calibration markings and other figures on glass articles; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|732</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7324">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glass, ceramics and related decorative painters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glass, ceramics and related decorative painters decorate articles made of wood, metal, textiles, glass, ceramics and other materials, and plan, lay out and paint letters and designs to make signs. Tasks include - (a) painting designs on articles with a brush, by spraying, or by transferring designs using stencils, transfers, rubber stamps and other means; (b) applying, for decorative purposes, paint, glaze, enamel, stain, varnish, lacquer and similar materials on articles by spraying or dipping; (c) coating mirror glass with silver solutions; (d) laying out and painting letters and designs to make signs; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|732</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7331">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Handicraft workers in wood and related</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Handicraft workers in wood and related materials apply traditional techniques to prepare wood, straw, rattan, reeds, stone, clay, shells, and other materials, and carve, mould, assemble, weave, or paint and decorate various articles for personal or household use, or for decorative purposes. Tasks include - (a) preparing wood, straw, rattan, reeds, stone, shells, or similar materials; (b) carving, assembling, weaving, painting and decorating various articles for personal or household use such as salad bowls, serving-spoons, cutting-boards, trays, vases, jugs, baskets, straw hats, straw mats and similar objects; (c) carving, assembling, weaving and painting various decorative articles such as statues and other sculptures, chess pieces, jewellery, and similar objects; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|733</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7332">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Handicraft workers in textile, leather and materials</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Handicraft workers in textile, leather and related materials apply traditional techniques and patterns to produce woven fabrics, knit- ted, embroidered, woven and other garments and articles for household use, as well as traditional footwear, handbags, belts and other accessories. Tasks include - (a) spinning and dyeing with natural dyestuffs, wool, cotton and other fibres; (b) lace-making and weaving, knitting, or embroidering various garments and articles for household use; (c) preparing and dyeing hides with natural dyestuffs and making traditional footwear or handbags, belts and other accessories; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|733</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7341">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Compositors, typesetters and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Compositors, typesetters and related workers set and arrange printing type by hand or machine. Tasks include - (a) setting type by hand and printing copies with simple machines; (b) operating linotype, monotype and typecasting machines; (c) arranging set-up of type and spacing material and illustration blocks to make pages; (d) arranging pages in sequence for printing; (e) operating electronic key-boarding machines which enable characters to be converted into film, sensitised tape or paper for subsequent photo plate-making; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7342">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Stereotypers and electrotypers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Stereotypers and electrotypers make printing plates from set-up type by stereotyping and electroplating processes. Tasks include - (a) making moulds of set-up type with papier mache, wax or other materials; (b) making printing plates by casting metal in moulds of papier mch or other material bearing impression of type, or by putting lead alloy backing on copper shell made by electroplating moulds to reproduce type; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7343">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Printing engravers and etchers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Printing engravers and etchers engrave lithographic stones and printing plates, rollers, dies and blocks by various processes. Tasks include - (a) cutting designs through film applied to surface of lithographic stones; (b) engraving steel and copper plates, rollers, dies or wood, rubber and linoleum blocks by hand; (c) engraving metal plates and rollers by machine; (d) transferring designs from lithographic stone to metal plates; (e) performing all or several tasks in preparing printing plates by photogravure process; (f) etching metal plates or rollers with acid and retouching; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7344">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Photographic and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Photographic and related workers develop and process photographic film and make prints or slides. Tasks include - (a) processing black and white or colour film and plates to obtain negatives or transparent positives; (b) printing black and white or colour photographs; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7345">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bookbinders and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bookbinders and related workers bind covers to books and perform book-finishing operations. Tasks include - (a) binding books and periodicals by hand; (b) setting and operating bookbinding machines; (c) embossing designs or titles on books by hand or machine; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7346">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Silk-screen, block and textile printers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Silk-screen, block and textile printers cut stencils for use in silk-screen printing and print on paper, metal, textiles and other materials with silk-screens, blocks of rubber, wood or other materials, or engraved printing rollers. Tasks include - (a) cutting stencils for silk-screen printing; (b) printing on paper, metal, textiles and other materials by silk-screen process; (c) printing designs and patterns on cloth or wallpaper with engraved blocks or machines equipped with engraved rollers; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|734</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7411">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Butchers, fishmongers and related food preparers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Butchers, fishmongers and related food preparers slaughter animals, kill fish, clean, cut and dress meat and fish and prepare related food items or preserve meat, fish and other foods and food products by drying, salting or smoking. Tasks include - (a) slaughtering animals or killing fish; (b) flaying and trimming carcasses; (c) cutting and dressing meat and fish for sale or further processing; (d) preparing ingredients and making sausages and similar products using simple chopping, mixing and shaping machines; (e) curing meat, fish and other foods; (f) operating smokehouses or ovens to smoke meat, fish and other foodstuffs; (g) cooking or in other ways preparing meat, fish and related food items for sale; (h) performing related tasks; (i) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7412">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bakers, pastry-cooks and confectionery makers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bakers, pastry-cooks and confectionery makers make various kinds of bread, cakes, and other flour products, as well as handmade chocolate and sugar confectionery. Tasks include - (a) making bread, cakes, biscuits, pastries, pies and other flour products; (b) making handmade confectionery from mixtures of sugar, chocolate and other ingredients with the help of tools and some machines; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7413">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Dairy-products makers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Dairy products makers process butter and various types of cheese, cream or other dairy products. Tasks include - (a) boiling milk, separating cream from milk, churning cream into butter; (b) curdling milk, heating curd until it reaches desired firmness, draining curd and finally placing cheese into moulds to press it into shape; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7414">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Fruit, vegetable and related preservers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Fruit, vegetable and related preservers process or preserve fruit, nuts and related foods in various ways including cooking, drying, salting, or juice or oil extraction. Tasks include - (a) extracting juices from various fruits; (b) extracting oils from oil-bearing seeds, nuts or fruits; (c) cooking, salting or drying fruit, vegetables and related foods; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7415">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Food and beverage tasters and graders</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Food and beverage tasters and graders inspect, taste and grade various types of agricultural products, food and beverages. Tasks include - (a) inspecting, testing and tasting agricultural products, food and beverages at various stages of processing to determine quality and grade into appropriate class; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7416">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Tobacco preparers and tobacco products makers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Tobacco preparers and tobacco products makers prepare tobacco leaves and make various tobacco products. Tasks include - (a) grading cured tobacco leaves by type, quality and locality where grown; (b) mixing tobacco leaves according to formula to obtain a blend of distinct flavour; (c) tending vacuum container which moistens tobacco for further processing; (d) removing midribs and stalks from tobacco leaves and shredding tobacco; (e) making cigars, cigarettes, snuff and other tobacco products by hand or with simple machines; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|741</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7421">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Wood treaters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood treaters season and preserve wood. Tasks include - (a) operating steam-heated kilns to season wood; (b) treating wood with chemicals to protect it against decay or parasites; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|742</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7422">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Cabinet makers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Cabinet-makers and related workers, by using tools and woodworking machines, make, decorate and repair wooden furniture, wheels or other wooden parts of vehicles, wooden fittings, patterns, models and other items such as pipes, wooden skis, shoes, or sports racquets and sticks. Tasks include - (a) making and repairing wooden articles, such as cabinets and other furniture, using woodworking machines and hand tools; (b) making and repairing wooden vehicles, wheels or other wooden parts of vehicles; (c) making and repairing wooden articles, such as patterns, scale models and mock-ups, casks, tobacco pipes, wooden skis, shoes or sports racquets or sticks; (d) decorating furniture and fixtures by inlaying wood, applying veneer and carving designs; (e) finishing surfaces of wooden articles or furniture; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|742</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7423">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Woodworking machine setters and setter-operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Woodworking-machine setters and setter-operators set or set and operate woodworking machines, such as precision sawing, shaping, planing, boring, turning and woodcarving machines. Tasks include - (a) setting and adjusting various kinds of machines for operation by others; (b) setting and operating one or several types of woodworking machines; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|742</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7424">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Basketry weavers, brush makers and related</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Basketry weavers, brush makers and related workers make wicker furniture, brushes and brooms and weave baskets. Tasks include - (a) making wicker furniture from peeled and softened rattan, reeds, rushes, willow branches and similar materials; (b) making various kinds of baskets by interlacing osier, rattan, reeds, rushes or similar materials; (c) selecting and preparing brush materials, such as bristles, nylon, fibres and wire, and setting them in brush base; (d) selecting and preparing materials, such as broom corn, bass and whisker fibre, and fastening them to broom handles; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|742</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7431">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Fiber preparers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Fibre preparers prepare wool, cotton,flax, jute, hemp and other natural textile fibres for spinning and winding. Tasks include - (a) grading and classifying natural textile fibres; (b) washing wool fibres; (c) cleaning and fluffing textile fibres; (d) forming fibres into sliver, combing them, combining sliver into sliver laps or forming sliver into rove; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7432">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Weavers, knitters and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Weavers, knitters and related workers spin and wind yarn by hand, weave materials on hand looms, make carpets by using a knotting technique, knit garment fabrics by hand or hand- operated machine or perform similar manufacturing tasks by hand or hand-operated machine. Tasks include - (a) spinning and winding yarn by hand; (b) drawing warp threads into loom by hand; (c) weaving plain or figured cloth, tapestry, lace, carpet or other fabrics on hand looms; (d) making carpets by using a knotting technique; (e) knitting garments and other articles on hand-operated machine or by hand; (f) crocheting or making braid by hand; (g) making nets by hand; (h) performing related tasks; (i) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7433">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Tailors, dressmakers and hatters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Tailors, dressmakers and hatters make suits, dresses and other garments from textile fabrics, leather or any other material except fur, carry out alterations and repairs, or make hats, or participate in the manufacture of ready-to-wear garments. Tasks include - (a) making overcoats, suits, skirts, shirts, blouses, lingerie, corsetry and similar garments often to clients\' individual requirements; (b) participating in the manufacture of ready-to-wear clothing; (c) making hats; (d) altering, restyling and repairing garments; (e) making and caring for costumes used in theatrical, television and motion picture productions; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7434">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Furriers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Furriers and related workers make, alter, repair and restyle garments and other articles made of fur, or participate in the manufacture of ready-to-wear fur garments. Tasks include - (a) choosing, stretching and trimming dressed furs to conform to the chosen pattern outline of fur garments or other articles; (b) making coats, jackets and other fur garments and articles; (c) participation in the manufacture of ready-to-wear fur clothing; (d) reclaiming furs or skins from old coats, gluing fabric to interior of fur coats and trimming blocked fur garments; (e) altering, restyling and repairing fur garments and other fur articles; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7435">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Textile, leather and related pattern-makers and</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Textile, leather and related pattern-makers and cutters make patterns and mark and cut textile, leather and other materials in the manufacture of garments, gloves and miscellaneous products. Tasks include - (a) drawing and cutting out patterns for making suits, dresses, shirts, blouses, gloves, hats and caps and other garments; (b) making outlines of patterns on cloth, light leathers or other materials to guide cutting; (c) cutting material according to pattern outline for making up garments, gloves and related items; (d) performing pattern-making, marking and cutting tasks in the manufacture of other products such as soft furnishings, canvas goods and umbrellas; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7436">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Sewers, embroiderers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Sewers, embroiderers and related workers sew together, repair and decorate garments, gloves and other products of textile, fur, leather and other materials by hand or by using simple sewing machines, and perform various related tasks. Tasks include - (a) performing various sewing tasks in making, altering and repairing articles of textile, leather and other materials; (b) embroidering decorative designs on garments or materials; (c) sewing sails, tents, awnings and similar articles; (d) assembling and covering umbrellas; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7437">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Upholsterers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Upholsterers and related workers upholster furniture, make mattresses, or make and install interior decorations of textile, leather and similar materials. Tasks include - (a) installing, arranging and securing springs, padding and covering material to furniture frames; (b) fitting and installing covers and cushioning for seats and other furnishings on vehicles, such as motor cars, railways coaches and aircraft; (c) making mattresses; (d) fitting and installing soft furnishings and interior decorations of textile, leather and similar materials; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|743</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7441">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Pelt dressers, tanners and fellmongers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Pelt dressers, tanners and fellmongers prepare fur- and wool-bearing pelts for making garments and other products, and make leather from hides and skins. Tasks include - (a) sorting and grading pelts, hides and skins; (b) removing flesh and fat from pelts before curing; (c) removing flesh and hair from hides; (d) removing long, coarse hair from pelts and trimming underlying hair to even length; (e) operating machine to split hides edgeways; (f) treating hides to convert them into leather; (g) applying dyes to fur pelts; (h) dressing and applying dyes and stains to leather; (i) stretching and smoothing dressed pelts; (j) performing related tasks; (k) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|744</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="7442">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Shoe-makers and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Shoe-makers and related workers make and repair standard or special footwear and, except for leather garments, hats and gloves, make natural or synthetic leather articles, such as luggage, handbags, and belts, or participate in the manufacture of shoes and related goods. Tasks include - (a) making patterns to guide the cutting of shoe parts; (b) cutting out, preparing and fitting together shoe parts; (c) sewing shoe parts together; (d) making standard or orthopaedic footwear to individual requirements; (e) making other special types of footwear to order; (f) examining and finishing footwear; (g) repairing footwear; (h) making and repairing articles such as saddles and harnesses for animals, luggage, handbags, brief-cases, leather bags and other accessories; (i) cutting out, shaping and padding parts for making leather articles; (j) sewing and stitching leather parts by hand or machine; (k) performing related tasks; (l) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|744</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
  </configurationGroup>
</I2CEConfiguration>