<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE I2CEConfiguration PUBLIC "SYSTEM"
"I2CE_Configuration.dtd">
<I2CEConfiguration name="isco-88-major-08">
  <metadata>
    <displayName>ISCO 88 Job Codes</displayName>
    <description>The ISCO 88 Job Codes</description>
    <version>4.3.0</version>
    <requirement name="isco-88">
      <atLeast version="4.3" />
      <lessThan version="4.4" />
    </requirement>
  </metadata>
  <configurationGroup name="formsData" path="/I2CE/formsData/forms">
    <displayName>Forms Data</displayName>
    <description>Form data saved in magic data</description>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_major">
      <configurationGroup name="8">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PLANT AND MACHINE OPERATORS AND ASSEMBLERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Plant and machine operators and assemblers operate and monitor industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment on the spot or by remote control, drive and operate trains, motor vehicles and mobile machinery and equipment, or assemble products from component parts according to strict specifications and procedures. The work mainly calls for experience with and an understanding of industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment as well as an ability to cope with machine-paced operations and to adapt to technological innovations. Most occupations in this major group require skills at the second ISCO skill level. Tasks performed by plant and machine operators and assemblers usually include: operating and monitoring mining or other industrial machinery and equipment for processing metal, minerals, glass, ceramics, wood, paper, or chemicals, as well as operating and monitoring water-treating or electrical-power- generating installations, and related plant; operating and monitoring machinery and equipment used to produce articles made of metal, minerals, chemicals, rubber, plastics, wood, paper, textiles, fur, or leather, and which process foodstuffs and related products operating printing and bookbinding machines; driving and operating trains and motor vehicles; driving, operating and monitoring mobile industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment; assembling products from component parts according to strict specifications and procedures. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_sub_major">
      <configurationGroup name="81">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>STATIONARY-PLANT AND RELATED OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Stationary-plant and related operators operate and monitor, on the spot or by remote control, industrial plant for mining or for the processing of metal, minerals, glass, ceramics, wood, paper, chemicals, or water-treating, electrical-power-generating and other purposes, as well as automated and semi-automated assembling processes and industrial robots. The work mainly calls for experience with and an understanding of the industrial plant which is being operated and monitored. Ability to cope with machine-paced operations and to adapt to innovations in machinery and equipment is often required. Tasks performed by workers in this sub-major group usually include: operating and monitoring industrial plant for mining or for the processing of metal, minerals, glass, ceramics, wood, paper, chemicals, or water-treating, electrical-power-generating and other purposes-, operating and monitoring automated or semi- automated assembly lines as well as industrial robots. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|8</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="82">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>MACHINE OPERATORS AND ASSEMBLERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Machine operators and assemblers operate and monitor industrial machines, on the spot or by remote control, or they assemble products from parts according to strict specifications and procedures. The work mainly calls for experience with and an understanding of the industrial machinery and equipment which is being operated and monitored. Ability to cope with machine- paced operations and to adapt to technological innovations is often required. Tasks performed by workers in this sub-major group usually include: operating and monitoring machines which produce goods made of metal, minerals, chemicals, rubber, plastics, wood, paper, textiles, fur and leather, and which process foodstuffs and related products; operating printing and bookbinding machines; operating product-packing and labelling machines; assembling products from component parts according to strict specifications and procedures. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|8</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="83">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>DRIVERS AND MOBILE-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Drivers and mobile-plant operators drive and tend trains and motor vehicles, or drive, operate and monitor mobile industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment, or execute deck duties on board ship and other water-borne craft. The work mainly calls for experience with and an understanding of the machinery and equipment which is being operated and monitored. Ability to cope with machine-paced operations and to adapt to technological innovations is often required. Tasks performed by workers in this sub-major group usually include: driving and tending trains and motor vehicles: driving, operating and monitoring mobile industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment ; carrying out deck duties on board ship and other water-borne craft. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_major">
            <value>isco_88_major|8</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_minor">
      <configurationGroup name="811">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>MINING- AND MINERAL-PROCESSING-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Plant and machine operators and assemblers operate and monitor industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment on the spot or by remote control, drive and operate trains, motor vehicles and mobile machinery and equipment, or assemble products from component parts according to strict specifications and procedures. The work mainly calls for experience with and an understanding of industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment as well as an ability to cope with machine-paced operations and to adapt to technological innovations. Most occupations in this major group require skills at the second ISCO skill level. Tasks performed by plant and machine operators and assemblers usually include: operating and monitoring mining or other industrial machinery and equipment for processing metal, minerals, glass, ceramics, wood, paper, or chemicals, as well as operating and monitoring water-treating or electrical-power- generating installations, and related plant; operating and monitoring machinery and equipment used to produce articles made of metal, minerals, chemicals, rubber, plastics, wood, paper, textiles, fur, or leather, and which process foodstuffs and related products operating printing and bookbinding machines; driving and operating trains and motor vehicles; driving, operating and monitoring mobile industrial and agricultural machinery and equipment; assembling products from component parts according to strict specifications and procedures. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="812">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>METAL-PROCESSING-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal-processing-plant operators operate and monitor ore- smelting, metal converting and refining furnaces, metal-rolling mills, metal-heat-treating- or metal-extrusion plant. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring furnaces for ore-smelting, melting, refining, converting or reheating metal, as well as plant for rolling, extruding or shaping metal. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="813">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>GLASS, CERAMICS AND RELATED PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glass, ceramics and related plant operators operate and monitor kilns, furnaces and other machinery and equipment used in the manufacture of glass as well as ceramic products. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring kilns, furnaces and other machinery and equipment used for making glass as well as ceramic products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="814">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>WOOD-PROCESSING- AND PAPERMAKING-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood-processing- and papermaking-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which saw, cut and grind wood in preparation for further use, convert wood and other materials into pulp, and make paper from pulp. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machinery and equipment which process wood for further use, convert wood and other materials into pulp, and make paper from pulp. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="815">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>CHEMICAL-PROCESSING-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Chemical-processing-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which process chemicals and related materials to obtain products with desirable properties. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machinery and equipment for processing chemicals by crushing, heating, mixing, distilling or filtering to obtain products with desirable properties, or plant for treating petroleum and petroleum-based products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="816">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>POWER-PRODUCTION AND RELATED PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Power-production and related plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment in an electrical-power- generating plant, and water-treatment, incinerator and related plant, and operate and maintain ships and other types of steam- engines, as well as boilers. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machinery and equipment for producing electric power-operating and monitoring steam-engines and boilers and other stationary machinery and equipment such as incinerators or water-treatment plant and pumping stations. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="817">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>AUTOMATED-ASSEMBLY-LINE AND INDUSTRIAL-ROBOT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Automated-assembly-line and industrial-robot operators operate and monitor automated or semi-automated assembly lines as well as industrial robots. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring automated or semi-automated assembly lines as well as industrial robots.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|81</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="821">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>METAL- AND MINERAL-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal- and mineral-products machine operators operate and monitor metalworking machines, or make products composed primarily of non-metallic mineral materials. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring metalworking machines such as lathes, power shears, and boring, grinding and metal-sawing machine tools, or machines to extrude, mould, mix, grind and cut various precast cement, concrete and stone products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="822">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>CHEMICAL-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Chemical-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which process a variety of chemicals and other ingredients to produce pharmaceuticals, toiletries, explosives, photographic or other chemical products, or to finish, plate and coat metal articles. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machines which mould, filter, ferment, mix, blend and otherwise process chemicals and other materials to give them the desired properties for further industrial production, or to make finished products; operating and monitoring machines which finish, plate and coat metal products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="823">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>RUBBER- AND PLASTIC-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Rubber- and plastic-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which knead and blend rubber and rubber compounds, and produce various components and products from natural and synthetic rubber and plastics. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machines which knead and blend rubber and rubber compounds, and produce various components and products from natural and synthetic rubber and plastics. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="824">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>WOOD-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood-products machine operators operate and monitor automatic and semi-automatic woodworking machines which perform repetitive work and are always set up by woodworking-machine setters. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring woodworking machines for sawing, shaping, boring, planing, turning or carving wood. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="825">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>PRINTING-, BINDING- AND PAPER-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Printing-, binding- and paper-products machine operators operate and monitor various types of printing and copying machines, or machines which bind and emboss books or which produce various articles from paper, paperboard and similar materials. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring various types of printing and copying machines, or machines which bind and emboss books or which produce various articles from paper, paperboard and similar materials. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="826">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>TEXTILE-, FUR- AND LEATHER-PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Textile-, fur- and leather-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which prepare fibres and yarns, or hides and pelts, and manufacture or dry-clean textiles, or fur and leather articles. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machines which prepare fibres and spin and wind yarn and thread; weave and knit ; manufacture machine-made garments from various materials; bleach, dye and clean textile garments; prepare hides, skins, pelts or fur to make leather; or make footwear and related products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="827">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>FOOD AND RELATED PRODUCTS MACHINE OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Food and related products machine operators operate and monitor machines which process foodstuffs and manufacture food and related products for human and animal consumption. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machines for slaughtering animals and cutting carcasses and fish into pieces for storage or sale manufacturing meat and fish products: processing milk and cream and manufacturing dairy products; crushing and grinding grain, spices or similar foodstuffs, making bread, pasta and related products; processing fruit, nuts and vegetables-, processing and refining sugar; processing tea, coffee and cocoa, or producing beer, wine, spirits and other beverages, or tobacco products. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="828">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>ASSEMBLERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Assemblers assemble components into products according to strictly laid down procedures. The products worked on may be moved from one worker to the next along assembly lines. Tasks performed usually include: assembling components into various types of products according to strictly laid down procedures.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="829">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>OTHER MACHINE OPERATORS AND ASSEMBLERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Other machine operators and assemblers operate and monitor machines which pack, label, and, if needed, add revenue stamps to products, packages and containers, or assemble, according to strictly laid down procedures, products whose component parts are made of a wide range of materials. Tasks performed usually include: operating and monitoring machines which pack, label and, if needed, add revenue stamps to products, packages and containers; assembling, according to strictly laid down procedures, products whose components are made of a wide range of materials. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|82</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="831">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>LOCOMOTIVE-ENGINE DRIVERS AND RELATED WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Locomotive-engine drivers and related workers drive locomotive engines to transport freight or passengers, manoeuvre railway coaches or operate railway signals. Tasks performed usually include: driving railway engines, operating railway signals, switching rolling stock and making up trains in railway yards. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|83</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="832">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>MOTOR-VEHICLE DRIVERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Motor-vehicle drivers drive and tend motor vehicles to transport materials, goods and passengers. Tasks performed usually include: driving and tending motorcycles, cars, taxis, trams and buses, heavy trucks, lorries and vans, in order to transport materials, goods, and passengers. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|83</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="833">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>AGRICULTURAL AND OTHER MOBILE-PLANT OPERATORS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Agricultural and other mobile-plant operators drive, tend, operate and monitor agricultural and other machinery and equipment for handling materials and heavy objects. Tasks performed usually include: driving, tending, operating and monitoring tractors and other specialised machinery in agricultural use, or earth-moving, hoisting, lifting and related equipment. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|83</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="834">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>SHIPS' DECK CREWS AND RELATED WORKERS</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Ships\' deck crews and related workers carry out deck duties on board ship and similar duties on board other water-borne craft. Tasks performed usually include; standing look-out watches at sea and in harbour, steering ship according to instructions, and cleaning, painting and maintaining ship and its deck equipment as required. Supervision of other workers may be included.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_sub_major">
            <value>isco_88_sub_major|83</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
    <configurationGroup name="isco_88_unit">
      <configurationGroup name="8111">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Mining-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Mining-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which cut channels in a mine or quarry workface or drill holes for blasting, or they operate continuous-mining machines. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machinery for cutting channels in a mine or quarry workface or for drilling blasting holes in mines or quarries; (b) operating and monitoring continuous mining machines; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|811</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8112">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Mineral-ore- and stone-processing-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Mineral-ore- and stone-processing-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment for processing mineral ore and stone. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring equipment which crushes and breaks lumps of minerals and stones to required size; (b) operating and monitoring washing, separating, leaching, precipitating, filtering, extracting and combining equipment to wash mineral ores in order to remove waste material; (c) combining mineral ores with solvents to facilitate further processing; (d) separating metal or mineral concentrates from ore or alluvial deposits by thickening, flotation, gravity separation, filtration, or magnetic or electrostatic separation; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|811</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8113">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Well drillers and borers and related</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Well drillers and borers and related workers erect and operate drilling machinery and equipment and perform related tasks in the sinking and operation of wells. Tasks include - (a) preparing and operating derrick pipe-handling devices and slush pumps; (b) operating rotary- or percussion-drilling machinery and equipment to drill oil or gas wells; (c) cleaning and servicing oil or gas wells and replacing pumping rods, casings and tubings; (d) setting up and operating drilling machinery and equipment to drill wells or bores other than for oil or gas; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|811</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8121">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Ore and metal furnace operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Ore and metal furnace operators operate and monitor ore- smelting, metal-converting and refining furnaces. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring blast furnaces to smelt ores for the production of ferrous or non-ferrous metals; (b) operating and monitoring furnaces to convert or refine pig- iron or scrap-metal to produce steel; (c) operating and monitoring furnaces to convert or refine non- ferrous metals; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|812</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8122">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal melters, casters and rolling-mill operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal melters, casters and rolling-mill operators operate and monitor rolling mills to roll metal, or furnaces to melt or reheat metal, or machines to cast metal. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring furnaces to melt ferrous and non- ferrous metal for casting; (b) operating and monitoring furnaces to reheat stock metal forms prior to forging, power-pressing, rolling and further processing; (c) operating and monitoring rolling mills to shape hot or cold steel into shapes for further processing, or into final shapes; (d) operating and monitoring rolling mills to reduce or form hot or cold non-ferrous metal to specified shapes, such as plate, sheet or foil; (e) operating and monitoring rolls to form seamless tubes and pipes from billets which have been pierced longitudinally; (f) pouring molten metal into moulds and operating and monitoring casting machines (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|812</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8123">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal-heat-treating-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal-heat-treating-plant operators operate and monitor plant altering the physical properties of metal objects by heating, cooling and chemical treatment. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring furnaces which heat and cool metal objects to relieve internal stresses, restore ductility and refine grain structure; (b) operating and monitoring furnaces which harden steel objects; (c) operating and monitoring plant which imparts a hard skin and tough, ductile core to steel objects by treating them with chemicals, heating and quenching or cooling them; (d) operating and monitoring furnaces which reheat hardened steel objects to relieve stresses and to impart toughness; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|812</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8124">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal drawers and extruders</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal drawers and extruders operate and monitor machinery and equipment which draw and extrude metals to make wire, tubes and similar products. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring wire-drawing machines; (b) operating and monitoring machines to draw seamless metal tubing; (c) operating and monitoring extrusion presses to make metal rods, bars and seamless tubing; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|812</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8131">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glass and ceramics kiln and related operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Glass and ceramics kiln and related machine operators operate and monitor kilns, furnaces and other machinery and equipment used in the manufacture of glass, ceramics, porcelain or bricks. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring glass-making furnaces; (b) operating and monitoring glass-annealing furnaces to prevent or remove internal stresses ; (c) operating and monitoring tempering furnaces to toughen glass (d) operating and monitoring machines which shape glass articles by blowing or pressure-moulding; (e) operating and monitoring machines which draw or roll molten glass to a continuous sheet of flat glass; (f) operating and monitoring floating-glass production plant; (g) operating and monitoring machines which polish and level plate-glass surfaces; (h) operating and monitoring machines which make glass rods and tubes from molten glass by drawing or drawing and blowing; (i) operating and monitoring kilns which bake pottery and porcelain ware or which fix glazing and decoration by rebaking; (j) operating and monitoring kilns which bake bricks and tiles; (k) performing related tasks; (l) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|813</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8139">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Glass, ceramics and related plant operators elsewhere classified</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>This unit group covers glass and ceramics plant operators not classified elsewhere in Minor group 813, Glass and ceramics plant operators. For instance, here should be classified those who are engaged in operating and monitoring machinery and equipment used to mix ingredients for glass-making or for the preparation of clay, glaze and abrasives, or which extrude molten glass in order to form fibreglass filaments. In such cases tasks would include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which mix ingredients for glass-making; (b) operating and monitoring machines which prepare clay for the production of ceramics and bricks; (c) operating and monitoring machines for making glaze or abrasives (d) operating and monitoring machines which extrude molten glass to form fibreglass filaments ; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|813</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8141">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Wood-processing-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood-processing-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment for sawing wood, cutting veneer and making plywood, and otherwise prepare wood for further use. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring log in-feed and conveyor systems; (b) operating and monitoring head saws, resaws and multiblade saws to saw logs, cants, flitches, slabs or wings and remove rough edges from sawn timber; (c) operating and monitoring machines which cut veneer; (d) operating and monitoring plywood core-laying machines and hot-plate plywood presses; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|814</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8142">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Paper-pulp plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Paper-pulp plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which converts materials such as wood, rags, esparto, straw, scrap-pulp and paper into stock for use in papermaking. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring chipper and grinding machines which reduce logs to pulp; (b) operating and monitoring digesters which produce pulp from materials such as wood, rags, esparto, straw or scrap-pulp and scrap paper; (c) operating and monitoring machines which bleach wood pulp, rags, esparto, straw or scrap-pulp and scrap paper; (d) operating and monitoring machines which mix, beat and hydrate pulp and other ingredients to prepare stuff for making paper; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|814</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8143">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Papermaking-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Papermaking-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which makes paper, paper board and sheet pulp from pulp stock. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring section of papermaking machinery and equipment in which wet pulp is formed into paper or in which paper is dried, calendered, wound, slit and rewound; (b) operating and monitoring supercalenders used to impart gloss and finish to surface of paper; (c) operating and monitoring machinery and equipment used to glaze or impregnate paper with coating mixture; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|814</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8151">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Crushing-, grinding- and chemical-mixing-machinery operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Crushing-, grinding- and chemical-mixing-machinery operators operate and monitor machinery which crushes, grinds, mixes and blends chemicals and other materials used in chemical and related processes. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring mills and crushing machines which reduce solid chemicals and related materials to suitable size for further processing ; (b) operating and monitoring machines in which solids or liquids used in chemical and related processes are mixed or blended (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8152">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Chemical-heat-treating-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Chemical-heat-treating-plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which cook, roast and provide other types of heat treatment in chemical and related processes. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machinery and equipment which cook materials in order to purify, mix or compound them, give them special properties or effect chemical changes in them; (b) operating and monitoring ovens, kilns or similar devices which heat substances in order to dry them, give them special properties or effect chemical changes in them ; (c) operating and monitoring driers for the processing of chemicals and related materials; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8153">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Chemical-filtering- and separating-equipment operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Chemical-filtering- and separating-equipment operators operate and monitor machines and equipment which filter and separate chemicals and related materials. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring equipment in which solutions are forced, under pressure, through a filtering unit; (b) operating and monitoring equipment in which solutions are vacuum-drawn through filtering media fitted to a rotating drum; (c) operating and monitoring machines which separate substances by centrifugal force; (d) operating and monitoring equipment which removes sediment and water from crude oil; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8154">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Chemical-still and reactor operators (except petroleum natural gas)</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Still and reactor operators (except petroleum and natural gas) operate and monitor equipment which distils and refines chemicals, except petroleum. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring equipment in which crude liquid chemicals are treated to refine or separate them into their chemical constituents; (b) operating and monitoring equipment which performs a sequence of operations in a chemical reaction process; (c) operating and monitoring evaporation tanks, vacuum pans or similar devices to concentrate solutions and suspensions; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8155">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Petroleum- and natural-gas-refining-plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Petroleum- and natural-gas-refining plant operators operate and monitor plant which refines, distils and treats petroleum, petroleum-based products and by-products, or natural gas. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring plant which removes sulphur from petroleum and petroleum-based products, and byproducts; (b) operating and monitoring pumps which circulate petroleum products or water and chemical solutions through refinery; (c) operating and monitoring stills which distil or refine petroleum products; (d) operating and monitoring machines which blend petrol with chemicals and other additives; (e) operating and monitoring machines which refine or otherwise treat natural gas, (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8159">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Chemical-processing-plant operators not elsewhere classified</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>This unit group covers chemical-processing-plant operators not classified elsewhere in Minor group 815, Chemical-processing plant operators. For instance, here should be classified those who are engaged in operating and monitoring machinery and equipment which treat chemical solutions with bleaching reagents, produce coke or gas from coal, extrude and form natural or synthetic polymers into synthetic fibres, produce fertilisers, or extract and process radioactive materials. In such cases tasks would include - (a) operating and monitoring plant which treats chemical solutions with bleaching reagents; (b) operating and monitoring plant which produces coke or gas from coal; (c) operating and monitoring plant which extrudes or forms natural or synthetic polymers into synthetic fibres; (d) operating and monitoring fertiliser plant equipment; (e) operating and monitoring plant which separates and extracts radioactive materials from their ores or processes such materials; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|815</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8161">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Power-production plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Power-production plant operators operate and monitor machinery and equipment which produce electric or other power and control its distribution. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring coal-, oil- or natural-gas-fired steam-power-generating plant; (b) operating and monitoring nuclear-fuelled steam-power- generating plant; (c) operating and monitoring hydroelectric-power-generating stations; (d) operating and monitoring other power generating plant, such as solar, tidal, geo-thermal or wind energy; (e) controlling power output and distribution of electricity from power stations; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|816</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8162">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Steam-engine and boiler operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Steam-engine and boiler operators operate and monitor steam- engines and boilers on land and at sea. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring coal- or oil fired steam-engines or boilers on land and at sea; (b) performing\' related tasks (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|816</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8163">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Incinerator, water-treatment and related plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Incinerator, water-treatment and related plant operators operate and monitor various types of plant, such as incinerators, water treatment plant, air and gas compressors, pumping stations, refrigeration or heating and ventilation systems. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring incinerator machinery and equipment which burn garbage or other waste materials; (b) operating and monitoring machinery and equipment which purify and clarify water for human consumption or use and later disposal into natural water systems; (c) operating and monitoring air and gas compressors\'; (d) operating and monitoring pumping stations for transferring liquids, gases, semi-liquids and powdered substances from one location to another; (e) operating and monitoring refrigeration systems for cool or cold storage, or industrial processes; (f) operating and monitoring heating and ventilation systems ; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|816</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8171">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Automated-assembly-line operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Automated-assembly-line operators operate and monitor automated or semi-automated assembly lines. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring automated or semi-automated assembly lines; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|817</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8172">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Industrial-robot operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Industrial-robot operators load and unload industrial robots and perform related tasks. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring industrial robots ; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|817</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8211">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Machine-tool operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Machine-tool operators operate and monitor automatic or semi-automatic metalworking machines which perform repetitive work and are set up by machine-tool setters. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring one or more machine tools such as lathes, stamping presses, power shears, metal-bending, milling, planing, boring, drilling, grinding, honing or metal-sawing machines which may be numerically controlled or linked by an automatic-transfer machine ; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|821</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8212">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Cement and other mineral products machine</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Cement and other mineral products machine operators operate and monitor extrusion, moulding, mixing, grinding and cutting machines which manufacture and finish various precast concrete and stone products, or which make cast stone for building purposes. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring extrusion, moulding, grinding and cutting machines which manufacture and finish various precast concrete and stone products, such as flagstones, fencing posts, moulded pipe sections and trench liners, walling and partition slabs, building components, cable conduits, fume and dust extraction conduits; (b) operating and monitoring machines which mix sand, gravel, cement and water to make concrete ; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|821</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8221">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Pharmaceutical- and toiletry-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Pharmaceutical- and toiletry-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which process a variety of chemicals and other ingredients used in the production of pharmaceuticals and toiletries. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines for moulding, filtering, fermenting, heating, mixing, grinding, filling and sealing materials used in the production of pharmaceuticals, toiletries, detergents and related products; (b) operating controls to regulate temperature, pressure, flow and speed of operation ; (c) cleaning and disinfecting equipment; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|822</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8222">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Ammunition- and explosive-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Ammunition- and explosive-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which process a variety of chemicals and other ingredients in the production of ammunition and explosives. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which mix, blend and otherwise process chemicals to produce explosive substances such as nitrocellulose, gelignite and various types of propellants; (b) operating and monitoring machines which make fuses for explosives and pyrotechnics; (c) operating and monitoring machines which assemble and load shells, bombs, rockets, mines and similar devices; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|822</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8223">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal finishing-, plating- and coating-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal finishing-, plating- and coating-machine operators operate and monitor equipment which finishes, plates and coats metal articles or parts, in order to give them improved resistance to corrosion and abrasion, for decorative purposes, or to impart electrical or magnetic properties. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring equipment which cleans metal articles in preparation for electroplating, galvanising, enamelling or similar processes; (b) operating and monitoring electroplating equipment; (c) operating and monitoring hot-dip equipment used to coat iron and steel products (d) operating and monitoring machines which automatically coat wire with non ferrous metal (e) operating and monitoring equipment used to spray molten metal or other substances on metal products to provide a protective or decorative coating or to build up worn or damaged surfaces; (f) operating and monitoring equipment used to impart a rust- resistant finish to metal articles by treating them with chemicals and heating them; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|822</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8224">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Photographic-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Photographic-products machine operators operate and monitor equipment which makes photographic film and paper, and which processes exposed photographic film and makes prints. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring equipment which makes photographic film and paper; (b) operating and monitoring machines for coating and backing photographic plates; (c) operating and monitoring equipment which processes colour and black-and white films and plates to obtain negatives or transparent positives; (d) operating and monitoring equipment which prints black-and- white or colour photographs or which enlarges or reduces photographs; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|822</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8229">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Chemical-products machine operators not elsewhere classified</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>This unit group covers chemical-products machine operators not classified elsewhere in Minor group 822. Chemical-products machine operators. For instance here should be classified those who operate and monitor machines which produce chemical-based products such as linoleum, candles, halogen gases and related items. In such cases tasks would include: (a) operating and monitoring machines which make linoleum, candles, halogen gases and related chemical products; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|822</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8231">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Rubber-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Rubber-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which knead and blend rubber and rubber compounds, and produce various components and products, from natural and synthetic rubber, such as moulded footwear, domestic articles, insulating materials, industrial accessories, or tyres for bicycles, automobiles, tractors, aircraft and other vehicles. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which knead, mix and blend rubber and rubber compounds for further processing; (b) operating and monitoring machines which produce sheets of rubber or rubberised fabric by a rolling process ; (c) operating and monitoring machines which extrude compounded rubber or shape vulcanised rubber by moulding (d) operating and monitoring machines which build up tires on a form, vulcanise tires and mould or rebuild used tires; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|823</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8232">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Plastic-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Plastic-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which knead and blend compounds to obtain plastic materials and which make various plastic components and articles. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which knead and blend compounds to obtain plastic materials; (b) operating and monitoring machines which shape plastic materials by moulding, extrusion, cutting and other means; (c) operating and monitoring machines which laminate plastics and plastic impregnated materials; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|823</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8240">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Wood-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood-products machine operators operate and monitor automatic or semi-automatic woodworking machines which perform repetitive work and are always set up by woodworking-machine setters. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring one or more previously set up machines for sawing, shaping, boring, planing, turning or carving wood; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|824</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8251">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Printing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Printing-machine operators operate and monitor various types of machines which print on paper, tin plate and other materials. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring cylinder, platen, rotary, offset, direct lithographic, rotogravure, and wallpaper-printing presses, (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|825</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8252">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bookbinding-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bookbinding-machine operators operate and monitor machines which bind and emboss books. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring bookbinding machines ; (b) operating and monitoring pressing machines which emboss designs and titles on book covers; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|825</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8253">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Paper-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Paper-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which produce boxes, envelopes, bags and other goods from paper, paperboard, cardboard, cellophane and similar materials. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which glue paper to cardboard, cut it to the required length or cut and crease cardboard or paperboard to form box blanks; (b) operating and monitoring pressing machines which form drinking cups or other containers from paper, paperboard or cardboard; (c) operating and monitoring machines which cut, fold and glue paper to make envelopes and paper bags, or which form bags from other materials; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|825</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8261">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Fiber-preparing-, spinning- and winding-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Fibre-preparing, spinning- and winding-machine operators operate and monitor machines which prepare fibres, and spin, double, twist and wind yarn and thread. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which combine textile fibres into uniform blends; (b) operating and monitoring machines which clean and fluff textile fibres, transform them into sliver, comb them into sliver for first drawing, combine slivers into sliver lap or sliver laps into ribbon lap, combine several slivers into one attenuated strand of regular quality and weight; (c) operating and monitoring machines which transform sliver into roving; (d) operating and monitoring machines which spin thread and yarn from roving, wind two or more threads onto bobbin, twist two or more strands of yarn or thread into single heavier and stronger strand, or wind yarn or thread from one package to another; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8262">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Weaving- and knitting-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Weaving- and knitting-machine operators operate and monitor weaving and knitting machines and related equipment used to produce materials and fabrics. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines used to weave or knit plain or figured cloth, tapestry, lace, carpets, garments, hosiery or other fabrics or articles; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8263">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Sewing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Sewing-machine operators operate and monitor sewing machines to make textile, fur or leather garments or embroider ornamental designs on garments or other materials. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring standard or specialised single- or multiple-needle sewing machines to make or repair garments, gloves and miscellaneous pro ducts in textiles, fur or leather; (b) operating and monitoring standard or specialised single- or multiple-needle sewing machines to embroider ornamental designs on textiles or other materials (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8264">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bleaching-, dyeing- and cleaning-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bleaching-, dyeing- and cleaning-machine operators operate and monitor machines which bleach, dye, wash and otherwise treat fibres, yarn, or cloth or dry clean textile, fur and leather articles. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which treat textile products to make them lighter in colour or to give them a specific colour; (b) operating and monitoring machines which wash or dry-clean textile, fur or leather products to remove dirt, impurities, excess chemicals or natural gum; (c) operating and monitoring machines which shrink cloth or strengthen the weave by interlocking the fibres; (d) operating and monitoring machines which impregnate textiles with chemicals to render them waterproof; (e) operating and monitoring machines which treat silk to give it body and weight; (f) operating and monitoring machines which press, stretch, or impart lustre, or other type of finish to textiles; (g) performing related tasks; (h) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8265">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Fur and leather-preparing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Fur- and leather-preparing-machine operators operate and monitor various machines which prepare leather or treat fur- or wool-bearing pelts. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which remove flesh and fat from pelts before curing; (b) operating and monitoring machines which remove long coarse hair from fur pelts, trim hair to even length, and dye, stretch and smooth dressed pelts; (c) operating and monitoring machines which separate residual wool from skins, or flesh and hair from hides, and which split hides; (d) operating and monitoring machines which treat hides and skins in solutions and apply finishing product to convert them into leather; (e) operating and monitoring machines which apply dyes and stains to leather; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8266">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Shoemaking- and related machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Shoemaking- and related machine operators operate and monitor machines which produce and repair standard or special footwear, handbags and other accessories, mainly made of leather Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which mark patterns and cut shoe parts ; (b) operating and monitoring machines which sew shoe parts together, or edge, polish, or apply ornaments and perform finishing tasks; (c) operating and monitoring machines which produce luggage, handbags, belts and other accessories, as well as other items such as saddles, collars or harnesses; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8269">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Textile-, fur- and leather-products machine operators elsewhere classified</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>This unit group covers textile-, fur- and leather-products machine operators not classified elsewhere in Minor group 826, Textile-, fur- and leather-products machine operators. For instance, here should be classified those who are engaged in operating and monitoring machines which make hats or miscellaneous articles such as braids or other trimmings. In such cases tasks would include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which form and make hats out of textiles, fur or leather; (b) operating and monitoring machines which make miscellaneous articles such as braids or other trimmings; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|826</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8271">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Meat- and fish-processing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Meat- and fish-processing-machine operators operate and monitor machines used to slaughter animals, trim carcasses, prepare standard meat or fish cuts, and manufacture meat and fish products. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines used to slaughter animals and to cut carcasses or fish into standard pieces; (b) operating and monitoring machines used to mince and mix meat or fish; (c) operating and monitoring machines used to process meat and fish and manufacture various meat and fish products, such as sausages, smoked meat or smoked fish; (d) operating and monitoring machines used to produce canned or frozen meat and fish dishes; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8272">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Dairy-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Dairy-products machine operators operate and monitor machines which process milk and cream and make dairy products. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which pasteurise, homogenise and heat-treat milk and cream; (b) operating and monitoring machines which make condensed or powdered milk; (c) operating and monitoring machines which make butter cheese and other milk or milk-based products; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8273">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Grain- and spice-milling-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Grain- and spice-milling-machine operators operate and monitor machinery used to crush, grind, blend and otherwise process grain, spices and related foodstuffs for human or animal consumption. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machinery used for the production of flour, meal and animal feed and for processing rice ; (b) operating and monitoring milling machines used for grinding grain and spices; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8274">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Baked-goods, cereal and chocolate-products machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Baked-goods, cereal and chocolate-products machine operators operate and monitor mixing, blending, shaping and baking machines which produce cereals, bread, pastry, pasta, chocolate and related products from flour, cocoa and other ingredients. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which mix and blend flour with other ingredients to prepare dough for the production of bread, pastries, pasta and related products; (b) operating and monitoring machines which extrude and shape dough for the production of bread, pastries, pasta and related products; (c) operating and monitoring ovens used for baking bread, pastries, pasta and related products; (d) operating and monitoring machines used for making cereals-\' (e) operating and monitoring machines used for making chocolate and confectionery; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8275">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Fruit-, vegetable- and nut-processing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Fruit-, vegetable- and nut-processing machine operators operate and monitor machines which extract juice from fruit and vegetables or oil from oil-bearing seeds, nuts and fruit, and which process fruit, vegetables and nuts by drying, cooking, canning or freezing. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which extract juice from fruit and vegetables by heating or pressing; (b) operating and monitoring machines which extract and refine oil from oil-bearing seeds, nuts and fruit; (c) operating and monitoring machines which make margarine and similar products from animal and vegetable oils; (d) operating and monitoring machines which prepare fruit, vegetables and nuts for further processing ; (e) operating and monitoring machines which dry, cook, can, freeze or otherwise process fruit, vegetables and nuts (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8276">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Sugar production machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Sugar production machine operators operate and monitor machines which process sugar-cane and sugar-beet and produce refined sugar Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which crush sugar-cane or extract liquor from sugar-beet; (b) operating and monitoring tanks used to purify sugar liquor or produce sugar crystals from hot sugar liquor; (c) operating and monitoring machines which refine sugar-beet or sugar-cane by a continuous process; (d) operating and monitoring machines which extract and refine sugar juices from maple, palm and other vegetable sources\'. (e) operating and monitoring machines which process honey; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8277">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Tea-, coffee-, and cocoa-processing-machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Tea-, coffee- and cocoa-processing machine operators operate and monitor machines to blend and prepare tea leaves, coffee or cocoa beans and chicory roots. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines used to dry tea leaves, roll withered leaves or dry rolled leaves, and blend various grades of tea; (b) operating and monitoring machines used to cut coffee or cocoa berries and remove and wash off pulp, peel off husk from beans, and cure and blend beans; (c) operating and monitoring machines which roast blended coffee or cocoa beans or chicory roots; (d) operating and monitoring machines which crush tea or grind coffee, cocoa or chicory; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8278">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Brewers, wine and other beverage machine</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Brewers, wine and other beverage machine operators operate and monitor machines which mix, press, or malt and ferment grains and fruit to make malt liquors, wine and other alcoholic or non-alcoholic beverages, except fruit and vegetable juices. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which process barley and other grains used in making distilled and malt liquors, and controlling the fermentation process, (b) operating and monitoring machines which process grapes and other fruit used in making wines, and controlling the fermentation process; (c) operating and monitoring stills which increase or reduce the alcohol content of alcoholic beverages; (d) operating and monitoring machines which blend wines and liquors to obtain desired tastes and flavours; (e) operating and monitoring machines which make non-alcoholic beverages, except fruit and vegetable juices; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8279">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Tobacco production machine operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Tobacco production machine operators operate and monitor machines which process tobacco and make cigarettes and other tobacco products. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which process tobacco in preparation for manufacturing cigarettes and other tobacco products; (b) operating and monitoring machines which produce cigarettes and other tobacco products; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|827</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8281">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Mechanical-machinery assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Mechanical-machinery assemblers assemble the components or parts of mechanical machinery, according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the components or parts of mechanical machinery, engines and vehicles, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8282">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electrical-equipment assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electrical-equipment assemblers assemble the components or parts of electrical equipment, according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the components or parts of electrical equipment, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8283">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Electronic-equipment assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Electronic-equipment assemblers assemble the components or parts of electronic equipment, according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the components or parts of electronic equipment, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8284">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Metal-, rubber- and plastic-products assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Metal-, rubber- and plastic-products assemblers perform limited, specialised tasks in assembling the metal, rubber or plastic components or parts of various types of products such as toys, sports articles, bicycles, etc. , according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the metal, rubber or plastic components or parts of various types of products, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8285">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Wood and related products assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Wood and related products assemblers assemble the components or parts made from wood or related materials, of various types of products, according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the components or parts made from wood or related materials, of various types of products, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8286">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Paperboard, textile and related products assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Paperboard, textile and related products assemblers assemble the components or parts made from paperboard, textile, leather and related materials, of various types of products, according to strictly laid down procedures. Tasks include - (a) assembling the components or parts made from paperboard, textile, leather and related materials, of various types of products, according to strictly laid down procedures; (b) attaching metal, plastic or other fittings (c) performing related tasks-\' (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|828</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8290">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Other machine operators and assemblers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Other machine operators and assemblers operate and monitor machines which pack, label and, if needed, add revenue stamps to products, packages and containers, or assemble, according to strictly laid down procedures, products whose component parts are made of a wide range of materials. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring machines which wrap and pack various products, including liquid ones, for storage or shipment; (b) operating and monitoring machines which, by gluing or other methods, label products, packages and various containers, or add revenue stamps; (c) assembling, according to strictly laid down procedures, products whose component parts are made of a very wide range of materials; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|829</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8311">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Locomotive-engine drivers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Locomotive-engine drivers drive, or assist in driving, locomotive engines to transport passengers and freight. Tasks include - (a) driving or assisting in driving a steam, electric or diesel- electric locomotive engine ; (b) driving an underground or elevated passenger train; (c) driving a locomotive to haul carriages underground or on the surface of a mine or quarry; (d) performing related tasks; (e) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|831</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8312">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Railway brakers, signalers and shunters</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Railway brakers, signallers and shunters take charge of and safeguard railway freight trains during runs, control the movement of railway traffic by operating signals, switch rolling stock and make up trains in railway yards, make up trains for hauling in mines and control their movement. Tasks include - (a) taking charge of and safeguarding freight train during run; (b) controlling flow of railway traffic over section of line by operating signals and switches from control panel or signal box; (c) switching and coupling rolling stock in railway yards and sidings in accordance with orders about loading, unloading and make-up of trains; (d) making up trains for hauling by locomotive or cable and directing their movement along haulageways in a mine or quarry; (e) performing related tasks; (f) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|831</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8321">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Motor-cycle drivers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Motor-cycle drivers drive and tend motor cycles or motorised tricycles equipped to transport materials, goods or passengers. Tasks include - (a) driving and tending motor cycle or motorised tricycle to transport materials, goods and passengers; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|832</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8322">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Car, taxi and van drivers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Car, taxi and van drivers drive and tend motor cars and vans to transport passengers, mail or goods. Tasks include - (a) driving and tending passenger cars or taxis ; (b) driving and tending cars, vans or small trucks to deliver mail or goods; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|832</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8323">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Bus and tram drivers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Bus and tram drivers drive and tend buses or street tramcars to transport passengers, mail or goods. (a) driving and tending motor bus, trolley bus or motor coach to transport local or long-distance passengers, mail or goods (b) driving and tending street tramcar transporting passengers; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|832</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8324">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Heavy-truck and lorry drivers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Heavy-truck and lorry drivers drive and tend heavy motor vehicles to transport goods, liquids and heavy materials over short or long distances. Tasks include - (a) driving and tending a heavy motor vehicle, such as a lorry with or without trailer or a dump-truck, to transport goods, liquids or heavy materials over short or long distances; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|832</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8331">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Motorized farm and forestry plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Motorised farm and forestry plant operators drive, tend, operate and monitor one or more types of motorised, mobile machinery or equipment used in farming or forestry operations. Tasks include - (a) driving and tending tractor or self-propelled ploughing, planting, harvesting, baling or other special-purpose farm machinery, or similar tractor-drawn equipment; (b) driving and tending tractor or self-propelled clearing, planting, harvesting, timber-carrying or other special- purpose forestry machinery; (c) performing related tasks; (d) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|833</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8332">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Earth-moving- and related plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Earth-moving- and related plant operators operate and monitor machines to excavate, grade, level and compact earth or similar materials and lay surfaces of asphalt and concrete. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring excavating machines, equipped with moveable shovel, grab-bucket or dragline bucket, to excavate and move earth, rock, sand, gravel or similar materials, or to tear down buildings or other structures; (b) operating and monitoring machines for digging trenches for sewers, drainage, water, oil, gas or similar pipelines; (c) operating and monitoring machines equipped with concave steel blade to move, distribute and level earth, sand, snow and other materials; (d) operating and monitoring equipment to remove sand, gravel and mud from bottom of body of water; (e) operating and monitoring machines for hammering wooden, concrete or steel piles into ground; (f) operating and monitoring power roller to compact and smooth layers of materials in making roads, pavements and similar work; (g) operating and monitoring machines which spread and smooth concrete or bituminous or tar preparations to construct roadways, roads or similar work; (h) performing related tasks; (i) supervising other worker\'s.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|833</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8333">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Crane, hoist and related plant operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Crane, hoist and related plant operators operate and monitor cranes and other hoisting equipment. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring mobile or stationary cranes with mobile or fixed jib or boom ; (b) operating and monitoring equipment for hoisting, lowering or raising men and materials on construction site or in mine; (c) operating and monitoring ski-lifts and similar equipment; (d) operating and monitoring machinery used to haul ferry or barge with goods, passengers and vehicles across short stretches of water; (e) operating and monitoring machinery to open and close bridge for the passage of road and water traffic; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other worker\'s.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|833</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8334">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Lifting-truck operators</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Lifting-truck operators drive, operate and monitor lifting- truck or similar vehicle to transport, lift and stack pallets with goods. Tasks include - (a) operating and monitoring lifting-truck and similar equipment to load and unload, transport, lift and stack goods and pallets in terminals, harbours, ware-houses, factories and other establishments; (b) performing related tasks; (c) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|833</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
      <configurationGroup name="8340">
        <configuration name="last_modified">
          <value>2009-07-15 11:07:57</value>
        </configuration>
        <configurationGroup name="fields">
          <configuration name="name">
            <value>Ships' deck crews and related workers</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="description">
            <value>Ship\'s deck crews and related workers carry out deck duties on board ship and similar duties on board other water-borne craft. Tasks include - (a) standing look-out watches at sea and when entering or leaving harbour or other narrow waters\'. (b) steering ship according to instructions; (c) handling mooring lines on board; (d) maintaining and, in some cases, operating ship\'s equipment, cargo gear, rigging, life-saving and fire-fighting appliances; (e) performing deck and hull cleaning, scraping, painting and other maintenance duties as required; (f) performing related tasks; (g) supervising other workers.</value>
          </configuration>
          <configuration name="isco_88_minor">
            <value>isco_88_minor|834</value>
          </configuration>
        </configurationGroup>
      </configurationGroup>
    </configurationGroup>
  </configurationGroup>
</I2CEConfiguration>